<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Derek DeSantis on Derek DeSantis</title>
    <link>https://derekdesantis.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Derek DeSantis on Derek DeSantis</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2018</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Oct 2017 00:00:00 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Nonnegative Canonical Polyadic Decomposition with Rank Deficient Factors</title>
      <link>https://derekdesantis.github.io/publication/ncpd-rk-deficient/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derekdesantis.github.io/publication/ncpd-rk-deficient/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operator Algebras Generated by Left Invertibles</title>
      <link>https://derekdesantis.github.io/talk/oa-left-inv-talk-defense/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derekdesantis.github.io/talk/oa-left-inv-talk-defense/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Operator algebras generated by partial isometries and their adjoints form the basis for some of the most well studied classes of C*-algebras. Representations of such algebras encode the dynamics of orthonormal sets in a Hilbert space. We instigate a research program on concrete operator algebras that model the dynamics of Hilbert space frames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The primary object of this thesis is the norm-closed operator algebra generated by a left invertible T together with its Moore-Penrose inverse. Of particular interest is when T satisfies a nondegeneracy condition called analytic. We show that T is analytic if and only if its adjoint belongs to an important class of operators called Cowen-Douglas. When the Fredholm index of T is -1, the algebra contains the compact operators, and any two such algebras are boundedly isomorphic if and only if they are similar. A classification of these algebras by K-theoritc means is then acquired.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operator Algebras Generated by Left Invertibles</title>
      <link>https://derekdesantis.github.io/publication/thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2019 00:00:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derekdesantis.github.io/publication/thesis/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operator Algebras Generated by a Single Left Invertible</title>
      <link>https://derekdesantis.github.io/publication/oa-gen-left-inf/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derekdesantis.github.io/publication/oa-gen-left-inf/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Example Page</title>
      <link>https://derekdesantis.github.io/tutorial/example/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Sep 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derekdesantis.github.io/tutorial/example/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;In this tutorial, I&amp;rsquo;ll share my top 10 tips for getting started with Academic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-1&#34;&gt;Tip 1&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;tip-2&#34;&gt;Tip 2&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A wavelet based approach to climate biome clustering</title>
      <link>https://derekdesantis.github.io/talk/climate-cluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Aug 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derekdesantis.github.io/talk/climate-cluster/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operator Algebras Generated by Left Invertibles</title>
      <link>https://derekdesantis.github.io/talk/oa-left-inv-talk/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Jun 2018 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derekdesantis.github.io/talk/oa-left-inv-talk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Operator algebras generated by partial isometries and their adjoints form the basis for some of the most well studied classes of C*-algebras.   The Toeplitz algebra is a classic example. The generator $M_z$ on the Hardy space $H^2(\mathbb{T})$ is isometric, and hence, left invertible. Motivated by questions from linear equations in Hilbert spaces (frame theory), we wish to understand particular types of operator algebras generated by left invertible operators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this talk, we investigate the norm closed operator algebra generated by a single left invertible operator $T$ in $\mathscr{B}(\mathscr{H})$ with a canonical left inverse (the Moore-Penrose inverse). This algebra, has rich operator algebraic structure that mimics the Toeplitz algebra. We are particularly interested in a class of left invertible operators we call \textit{analytic}. The adjoints of analytic left invertible operators are Cowen-Dogulas, an important class of operators that serve as a bridge between operator theory and complex geometry. Consequently, we can represent $T$ as $M_z$ on a reproducing kernel Hilbert space of analytic functions. Using tools of Cowen-Douglas theory, we reduce the challenge of classifying these algebras into more tractable geometric problems.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Climate Biome Clustering</title>
      <link>https://derekdesantis.github.io/project/climate-clustering/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derekdesantis.github.io/project/climate-clustering/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are many factors that determine how we perceive and ultimately classify the climate into distinct regions, or biomes.  For example, precipitation, temperature, flora and fauna are key ingredients in our delineation of biomes. Classifying biomes is akin to understanding the homogeneity of climate and resources on a local scale.  It is not only important that we can classify climate biomes, but also their evolution with the changing climate.  For emphasis, it is not possible to perform any meaningful environmental preservation without predetermined knowledge of what the environment is at a coarse scale.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Historically, the standard used to classify climate biomes has been the Köppen-Geiger (KG) model [1].  The KG model is an expert based judgment that describes climate zones based off of temperature and precipitation measurements.   The model utilizes a fixed decision tree, where each branch uses various information about temperature and precipitation. This heuristic allows one to broadly assess climate regions.  While KG is interpretable, it is overly simplistic and somewhat arbitrary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A solution to this problem is to move towards data-driven methods of classification.  Various authors have noted this, and have applied unsupervised models to classify the climate (see for example, [2], [3]).  These data driven approaches to climate clustering are an epistemological improvement over the use chosen heuristics of KG.  However, they still suffer from two key problems.  First, the algorithms themselves are user chosen, and therefore somewhat arbitrary themselves. There is no external measurement to measure how much one trusts the clustering result. Second, because the algorithms are dependent on the input data, they are dependent on the scale at which the data is acquired.  A priori, it is not clear how this &amp;ldquo;hidden parameter&amp;rdquo; of scale affects the overall clustering result. The goal of this project is to address both of these problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[1] Markus Kottek, Jürgen Grieser, Christoph Beck, Bruno Rudolf, and Franz Rubel. World map of the köppen-geigerclimate classification updated.Meteorologische Zeitschrift, 15(3):259–263, 2006.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[2] Pawel Netzel and Tomasz Stepinski. On using a clustering approach for global climate classification.Journal ofClimate, 29(9):3387–3401, 2016.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;[3] Jakob Zscheischler, Miguel D Mahecha, and Stefan Harmeling. Climate classifications: the value of unsupervisedclustering.Procedia Computer Science, 9:897–906, 2012.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Operator Algebras Modeling Dynamics of Frames</title>
      <link>https://derekdesantis.github.io/project/oa-from-frame/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derekdesantis.github.io/project/oa-from-frame/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For a Hilbert space $\mathscr{H}$, $y \in \mathscr{H}$ and  $T \in \mathscr{B}(\mathscr{H})$, the equation
\begin{equation}
T x = y
\end{equation}
has a solution whenever $T$ is left invertible.  For any left inverse $L$ of $T$, $x = L y$ is a solution.  More generally, if $T$ has closed range, $T$ has a &lt;em&gt;pseudo left inverse&lt;/em&gt;. Concretely, if $T \in \mathscr{B}(\mathscr{H})$ has closed range, restricting to $\ker(T)^\perp$ we obtain a new operator that is left invertible. Picking a left inverse $L$ for $T\mid_{\ker(T)^\perp}$, we find that $x = L y$ is a solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most applications, there is a canonical choice for the left inverse $L$.  Generally, this is the &lt;em&gt;Moore-Penrose inverse&lt;/em&gt;, denoted $T^\dagger$.  It is the unique left inverse such that $\ker(T^\dagger) = \mbox{ran}(T)^\perp$.  To construct $T^\dagger$, one considers $T$ mapping $\ker(T)^\perp$ to $\mbox{ran}(T)$.  From this perspective, $T$ is bijective, and thus boundedly invertible by the open mapping theorem. The unique inverse, once extended by zero, is $T^\dagger$. For instance, if $T$ is an isometry then $T^\dagger = T^*$, the adjoint of $T$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One subject where closed range operators are frequently used is &lt;em&gt;frame theory&lt;/em&gt;. A sequence {$f_n$} in a Hilbert space $\mathscr{H}$ is said to be a &lt;em&gt;frame&lt;/em&gt; if there exists constants $0&amp;lt; A \leq B$ such that
\begin{equation}
A ||x||^2 \leq \sum_n | \langle x, f_n \rangle |^2 \leq B ||x||^2
\end{equation}
for all $x \in \mathscr{H}$.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Associated to each Hilbert space frame {$f_n$} is a (canonical) dual frame {$g_n$}. Using this dual frame, one can reconstruct elements $f$ of the Hilbert space $\mathscr{H}$ in an analogous way to orthonormal basis:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\begin{equation}
f = \sum_{n \geq 1} \langle f, g_n \rangle f_n
\end{equation}&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is easy to see that orthonormal bases are frames, but not all frames need be orthogonal, norm one, or even contain a unique set of elements.  A frame does not enforce the rigidity of inner products that an orthonormal basis does - allowing for variation between individual frame elements (rather than just 0 or 1). The flexibility of the definition has engendered applications across signal processing and harmonic analysis. For instance, frames may be constructed for particular features of a problem that are precluded from orthogonal bases due to their requirement for linear independence.  Further, this extra redundancy helps to protect signals from degradation, ensuring that the effects of erasures are minimized.  The looseness of the structure allows one to construct the analog of frames for structures that don&amp;rsquo;t necessarily come equipped with suitable generalization of an orthonormal basis.  Indeed, certain classes of Hilbert C*-Modules and Banach spaces posses frames.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many questions concerning Hilbert space frames are inexorably tied to questions of closed ranged and left invertible operators.  All frames for closed subspaces of a Hilbert $\mathscr{H}$ spaces arise as the application of a closed range operator $T$ on a frame for $\mathscr{H}$. Properties of frames, such as rigidity and perturbation results also depend on the analysis of closed range operators.  With this groundwork of closed ranged operators and frame theory laid, we now describe our interest in generating concrete operator algebras.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A well-studied class of operator algebras are C&lt;em&gt;-algebras generated by partial isometries.    For example graph algebras, C&lt;/em&gt;-algebras generated partial isometries subject to constraints of a directed graph, reside here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Representations of graph C*-algebras arising from a directed graph may be described as follows. Given a directed graph, choose a Hilbert space for each vertex of the graph (with suitable dimension depending on loops of the graph).  After direct summing each of these spaces together, we obtain a Hilbert space $\mathscr{H}$ where each vertex corresponds to an orthogonal summand of $\mathscr{H}$.  By choosing orthonormal sequences for each of these closed, orthogonal subspaces of $\mathscr{H}$, we then pick partial isometries that map one summand to another, subject to the Cuntz-Krieger relations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The partial isometric generators of concrete graph algebras preserve orthonormal basis (that is, up to the kernels of the partial isometries).  The representation of the graph C&lt;em&gt;-algebra can be viewed as encoding the dynamics of walks on the graph.  A natural extension of these concrete graph C&lt;/em&gt;-algebras is one that encodes the dynamics of a frame.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One arrives at a such an extension by replacing &lt;em&gt;partial isometries and their adjoints&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;closed ranged operators and their Moore-Penrose inverses&lt;/em&gt;.  As discussed above, the closed range operators  preserve frame theoretic quantities.  In the isometric case, the Moore-Penrose inverse is the adjoint. Hence, such operator algebras reduce to the C&lt;em&gt;-algebraic case when the generators are isometric. Therefore, this class of operator algebras is the natural generalization of concrete graph C&lt;/em&gt;-algebras that integrates frame theory.  This leads us to the following general program:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Given a set of operators with closed range and their Moore-Penrose inverses construct the norm-closed algebra subject to the constraints of a directed graph. What is the structure of these algebras?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theory of Tensor Factorizations</title>
      <link>https://derekdesantis.github.io/project/tensor-factor-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derekdesantis.github.io/project/tensor-factor-theory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Data measured from a high-order complex system can be difficult to analyze. A convenient tool to store such data is in the form of a tensor, or d-way array. Each entry of the array describes the value obtained across the d independent parameters. Often, the dependencies between the indices is not clear, making interpretation of the data a demanding task.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most naturally occurring datasets are formed by directly observing and measuring quantities. As a result, the underlying or driving processes are usually unknown.  We call such variables hidden or latent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tensor factorizations are higher-order analogs to matrix factorizations.  The main goal of all tensor factorizations is to decompose the tensor into simpler objects, such as sums special products of matrices.  These atomized, simple building blocks often reflect the hidden processes that went into deriving the data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic: the website designer for Hugo</title>
      <link>https://derekdesantis.github.io/post/getting-started/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Apr 2016 00:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derekdesantis.github.io/post/getting-started/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Academic&lt;/strong&gt; is a framework to help you create a beautiful website quickly. Perfect for personal sites, blogs, or business/project sites. &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the latest demo&lt;/a&gt; of what you&amp;rsquo;ll get in less than 10 minutes. Then head on over to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start guide&lt;/a&gt; or take a look at the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Release Notes&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/academic.png&#34; alt=&#34;Screenshot&#34; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Key features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Easily manage various content including homepage, blog posts, publications, talks, and projects&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Extensible via &lt;strong&gt;color themes&lt;/strong&gt; and &lt;strong&gt;widgets/plugins&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write in &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/writing-markdown-latex/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown&lt;/a&gt; for easy formatting and code highlighting, with &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikibooks.org/wiki/LaTeX/Mathematics&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;LaTeX&lt;/a&gt; for mathematical expressions&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Social/academic network linking, &lt;a href=&#34;https://analytics.google.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Google Analytics&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&#34;https://disqus.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Disqus&lt;/a&gt; comments&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Responsive and mobile friendly&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Simple and refreshing one page design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multilingual and easy to customize&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;color-themes&#34;&gt;Color Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Academic is available in different color themes and font themes.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-default.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-default.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Ocean&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-ocean.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-ocean.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Dark&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-dark.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-dark.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Default&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-forest.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-forest.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;Coffee theme with Playfair font&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-coffee-playfair.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-coffee-playfair.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
  
  
  
    
  
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-1&#34; data-caption=&#34;1950s&#34; href=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-1950s.png&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img alt=&#34;&#34; src=&#34;https://raw.githubusercontent.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/master/images/theme-1950s.png&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;install&#34;&gt;Install&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can choose from one of the following four methods to install:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;one-click install using your web browser (recommended)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer using Git with the Command Prompt/Terminal app&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer by downloading the ZIP files&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;install on your computer with RStudio&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;quick-install-using-your-web-browser&#34;&gt;Quick install using your web browser&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://app.netlify.com/start/deploy?repository=https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Install Academic with Netlify&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Netlify will provide you with a customizable URL to access your new site&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;On GitHub, go to your newly created &lt;code&gt;academic-kickstart&lt;/code&gt; repository and edit &lt;code&gt;config.toml&lt;/code&gt; to personalize your site. Shortly after saving the file, your site will automatically update&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-git&#34;&gt;Install with Git&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Prerequisites:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://git-scm.com/downloads&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Git&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://gohugo.io/getting-started/installing/#quick-install&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download and install Hugo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart#fork-destination-box&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Fork&lt;/a&gt; the &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt; repository and clone your fork with Git:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;git clone https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart.git My_Website
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Note that if you forked Academic Kickstart, the above command should be edited to clone your fork, i.e. replace &lt;code&gt;sourcethemes&lt;/code&gt; with your GitHub username.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Initialize the theme:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;cd My_Website
git submodule update --init --recursive
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-zip&#34;&gt;Install with ZIP&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/sourcethemes/academic-kickstart/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract &lt;em&gt;Academic Kickstart&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/archive/master.zip&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt; and extract the &lt;em&gt;Academic theme&lt;/em&gt; to the &lt;code&gt;themes/academic/&lt;/code&gt; folder from the above step&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;install-with-rstudio&#34;&gt;Install with RStudio&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/install/#install-with-rstudio&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;View the guide to installing Academic with RStudio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;quick-start&#34;&gt;Quick start&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;If you installed on your computer, view your new website by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;hugo server
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now visit &lt;a href=&#34;http://localhost:1313&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;localhost:1313&lt;/a&gt; and your new Academic powered website will appear. Otherwise, if using Netlify, they will provide you with your URL.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Read the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Quick Start Guide&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to add Markdown content, customize your site, and deploy it. For inspiration, refer to the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/tree/master/exampleSite&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Markdown content&lt;/a&gt; which powers the &lt;a href=&#34;https://themes.gohugo.io/theme/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Demo&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Build your site by running the &lt;code&gt;hugo&lt;/code&gt; command. Then &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com/create-your-website-with-hugo/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;host it for free using Github Pages&lt;/a&gt; or Netlify (refer to the first installation method). Alternatively, copy the generated &lt;code&gt;public/&lt;/code&gt; directory (by FTP, Rsync, etc.) to your production web server (such as a university&amp;rsquo;s hosting service).&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;updating&#34;&gt;Updating&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to &lt;em&gt;star&lt;/em&gt; the project on &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Github&lt;/a&gt; to help keep track of updates and check out the &lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/updates&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;release notes&lt;/a&gt; prior to updating your site.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before updating the framework, it is recommended to make a backup of your entire website directory (or at least your &lt;code&gt;themes/academic&lt;/code&gt; directory) and record your current version number.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By default, Academic is installed as a Git submodule which can be updated by running the following command:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-bash&#34;&gt;git submodule update --remote --merge
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/update/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Check out the update guide&lt;/a&gt; for full instructions and alternative methods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;feedback-contributing&#34;&gt;Feedback &amp;amp; Contributing&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Please use the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/issues&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;issue tracker&lt;/a&gt; to let me know about any bugs or feature requests, or alternatively make a pull request.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For support, head over to the &lt;a href=&#34;http://discuss.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Hugo discussion forum&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;license&#34;&gt;License&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Copyright 2016-present &lt;a href=&#34;https://georgecushen.com&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;George Cushen&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Released under the &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/gcushen/hugo-academic/blob/master/LICENSE.md&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;MIT&lt;/a&gt; license.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Slides</title>
      <link>https://derekdesantis.github.io/slides/example-slides/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://derekdesantis.github.io/slides/example-slides/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h1 id=&#34;welcome-to-slides&#34;&gt;Welcome to Slides&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Academic&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;features&#34;&gt;Features&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Efficiently write slides in Markdown&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;3-in-1: Create, Present, and Publish your slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Supports speaker notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mobile friendly slides&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;controls&#34;&gt;Controls&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Next: &lt;code&gt;Right Arrow&lt;/code&gt; or &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Previous: &lt;code&gt;Left Arrow&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Start: &lt;code&gt;Home&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Finish: &lt;code&gt;End&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Overview: &lt;code&gt;Esc&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker notes: &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fullscreen: &lt;code&gt;F&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Zoom: &lt;code&gt;Alt + Click&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/hakimel/reveal.js#pdf-export&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;PDF Export&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;code&gt;E&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;code-highlighting&#34;&gt;Code Highlighting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Inline code: &lt;code&gt;variable&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Code block:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-python&#34;&gt;porridge = &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;
if porridge == &amp;quot;blueberry&amp;quot;:
    print(&amp;quot;Eating...&amp;quot;)
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;math&#34;&gt;Math&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In-line math: $x + y = z$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Block math:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;$$
f\left( x \right) = \;\frac{{2\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x - 4} \right)}}{{\left( {x + 4} \right)\left( {x + 1} \right)}}
$$&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;fragments&#34;&gt;Fragments&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Make content appear incrementally&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;{{% fragment %}} One {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} **Two** {{% /fragment %}}
{{% fragment %}} Three {{% /fragment %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;Space&lt;/code&gt; to play!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  One
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  &lt;strong&gt;Two&lt;/strong&gt;
&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&#34;fragment &#34; &gt;
  Three
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A fragment can accept two optional parameters:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;class&lt;/code&gt;: use a custom style (requires definition in custom CSS)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;weight&lt;/code&gt;: sets the order in which a fragment appears&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;speaker-notes&#34;&gt;Speaker Notes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Add speaker notes to your presentation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{% speaker_note %}}
- Only the speaker can read these notes
- Press `S` key to view
{{% /speaker_note %}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Press the &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view the speaker notes!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;aside class=&#34;notes&#34;&gt;
  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Only the speaker can read these notes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Press &lt;code&gt;S&lt;/code&gt; key to view&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;/aside&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;themes&#34;&gt;Themes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;black: Black background, white text, blue links (default)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;white: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;league: Gray background, white text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;beige: Beige background, dark text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;sky: Blue background, thin dark text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;night: Black background, thick white text, orange links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;serif: Cappuccino background, gray text, brown links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;simple: White background, black text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;solarized: Cream-colored background, dark green text, blue links&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;


&lt;section data-noprocess data-shortcode-slide
  
      
      data-background-image=&#34;/img/boards.jpg&#34;
  &gt;


&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-slide&#34;&gt;Custom Slide&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Customize the slide style and background&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-markdown&#34;&gt;{{&amp;lt; slide background-image=&amp;quot;/img/boards.jpg&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide background-color=&amp;quot;#0000FF&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
{{&amp;lt; slide class=&amp;quot;my-style&amp;quot; &amp;gt;}}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;custom-css-example&#34;&gt;Custom CSS Example&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let&amp;rsquo;s make headers navy colored.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Create &lt;code&gt;assets/css/reveal_custom.css&lt;/code&gt; with:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-css&#34;&gt;.reveal section h1,
.reveal section h2,
.reveal section h3 {
  color: navy;
}
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;questions&#34;&gt;Questions?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://discourse.gohugo.io&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Ask&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://sourcethemes.com/academic/docs/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
